<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Madhav Khosla</title><link>https://madhavkhoslaa.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Madhav Khosla</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 02:01:58 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://madhavkhoslaa.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Understanding Rust Ownership</title><link>https://madhavkhoslaa.github.io/draft/rustownership/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://madhavkhoslaa.github.io/draft/rustownership/</guid><description>Ownership is one of the features that make it different than so many programming languages and what makes it memory safe and a good language for concurrent programming. It solves problems like null pointers, dangling pointers, and data races without a garbage collector at the run time.
Understanding Rust Ownership How is data stored in the program? Stack Heap Data(variables in function arguments and defined) in the stack have a known type hence the size of the data in the stack is known at the time of compilation.</description></item><item><title>Automating your Linux Development using Ansible and GNU Stow</title><link>https://madhavkhoslaa.github.io/draft/ansible/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2022 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://madhavkhoslaa.github.io/draft/ansible/</guid><description>Automating your Linux Development using Ansible and GNU Stow</description></item><item><title>Creational Design Patterns: My lessons on it</title><link>https://madhavkhoslaa.github.io/posts/ceationaldesignpatterns/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://madhavkhoslaa.github.io/posts/ceationaldesignpatterns/</guid><description>Creational Design Patterns Creational design patterns provide various object creation mechanisms, which increase flexibility and reuse of existing code.
Why were they made and why should you care about reading them? You must have noticed in a larger code base where multiple classes dealing with the class instantiation becomes too hard, in fact in the case of languages like java where the ecosystem expects everything to be a class; a framework called spring had been developed to solve the problem of instantiating classes(and so much more).</description></item><item><title>SOLID Patterns: My lessons on it</title><link>https://madhavkhoslaa.github.io/posts/solid/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 04:01:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://madhavkhoslaa.github.io/posts/solid/</guid><description>SOLID is just an acronym for a few principles that Robert C. Martin compiled together. SOLID Design principles aim to make your code base extensible, easy to modify in the future, and easy to debug and fix. They are not rules just a bunch of thought ideas of segregation of logic and how to organize your code.
S =&amp;gt; Single Responsibility Principle
O =&amp;gt; Open Close Princple
L =&amp;gt; Liskov Substitution Principle</description></item><item><title>Caching: My lessons on it</title><link>https://madhavkhoslaa.github.io/posts/post1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://madhavkhoslaa.github.io/posts/post1/</guid><description>Caching is a cheap way to scale a system&amp;rsquo;s performance in very less time. Being cheap and easy to implement on the top of a existing system it also brings some problems such as invalidation and infrastructure for setting up the cache itself. Here I plan to talk about some lessons on caching that I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt in a few months.
Philosophy of Caching The supreme art of war is to subdue the enemy without fighting it - Sun Tzu</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://madhavkhoslaa.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://madhavkhoslaa.github.io/about/</guid><description>Hey, I’m Madhav; Join me in the pursuit of becoming a better software engineer. I plan to write here about what I learned and what seems to me to be the core of what you need to know as someone who is writing code and web applications.
What&amp;rsquo;s the deal here? A place where I am in control, with no censorship or manupilation. A place where my words don&amp;rsquo;t get mixed up with noise.</description></item></channel></rss>